<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Governance on Runink</title>
    <link>https://runink.org/tags/data-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Governance on Runink</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 08:13:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://runink.org/tags/data-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Automated Semantic Layers from Telemetry Events Are the Pillars of Data Observability Platforms</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/automated-semantic-layer-data-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/automated-semantic-layer-data-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-automated-semantic-layers-from-telemetry-events-are-the-pillars-of-data-observability-platforms&#34;&gt;Why Automated Semantic Layers from Telemetry Events Are the Pillars of Data Observability Platforms&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the era of streaming data, AI copilots, and self-service analytics, one truth has become unavoidable: &lt;strong&gt;you can’t observe what you can’t define&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Enter the &lt;strong&gt;automated semantic layer&lt;/strong&gt; — the missing connective tissue between raw telemetry and meaningful business context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When powered by continuous telemetry events, an automated semantic layer transforms fragmented observability metrics into &lt;strong&gt;a governed, contextual map of your entire data ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It’s how modern organizations are turning data observability from passive monitoring into &lt;strong&gt;active, explainable intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telemetry Data Supercharges Automated Reconciliation Domain Models</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/telemetry-data-reconciliation-domain-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/telemetry-data-reconciliation-domain-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;telemetry-led-automation-for-reliable-reconciliation&#34;&gt;Telemetry-Led Automation for Reliable Reconciliation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem-introduction&#34;&gt;Problem Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Telemetry data keeps piling up across our pipelines, yet most reconciliation routines still feel like slow manual patchwork. Every time metrics drift or a partner system sends malformed payloads, we scramble through log spelunking and spreadsheet cross-checks to explain mismatched totals. Automated data reconciliation based on domain models promises consistency, but we rarely trust the inputs enough to let algorithms decide the fixes. This post unpacks how rich telemetry streams become the connective tissue for reliable, automated reconciliation, especially when domain models drive rules, thresholds, and remediation playbooks designed for the realities of data professionals shipping analytics everyday at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Data Governance Supercharges AI Logistics ROI with LLM-Driven Drone Sourcing</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/data-governance-ai-logistics-roi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/data-governance-ai-logistics-roi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;AI tools like LLMs and autonomous drones are transforming logistics and procurement—but without strong data governance, their potential remains untapped. Learn how data quality, consistency, and compliance fuel ROI and give enterprises a competitive edge in the smart supply chain era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;maximizing-roi-in-ai-driven-logistics-why-data-governance-matters-in-industry40-procurement&#34;&gt;Maximizing ROI in AI-Driven Logistics: Why Data Governance Matters in Industry 4.0 Procurement&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-ai-drones-and-the-data-dilemma&#34;&gt;Introduction: AI, Drones, and the Data Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is revolutionizing logistics and supply chain operations. &lt;strong&gt;Industry 4.0&lt;/strong&gt; technologies like &lt;strong&gt;autonomous drones, IoT sensors, and large language models (LLMs)&lt;/strong&gt; are being deployed to automate deliveries and optimize procurement. From AI-powered route planning to smart strategic sourcing tools, companies are investing heavily in these innovations. But there’s a catch – all the &lt;strong&gt;AI in logistics&lt;/strong&gt; in the world won’t deliver value if it’s fed bad data. In fact, many organizations struggle to realize a return on investment (&lt;strong&gt;ROI&lt;/strong&gt;) from AI projects due to poor data quality and siloed information. This is where &lt;strong&gt;data governance&lt;/strong&gt; comes in. It might not sound as exciting as drones or machine learning, but it’s the secret sauce to maximizing the ROI of IT investments in AI-driven logistics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Dynamic Masking on Shared Snowflake Objects is Mandatory for Data-Driven Companies</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/dynamic-masking-snowflake-shared-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/dynamic-masking-snowflake-shared-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dynamic data masking on shared Snowflake objects is essential for compliant financial and insurance companies. It ensures regulatory alignment (GDPR, CCPA, HIPAA, etc.), strengthens data security, limits insider threats, and preserves real-time analytics integrity—enabling secure, scalable, and cost-efficient data sharing without compromising sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s landscape, compliant financial and insurance companies face unprecedented regulatory scrutiny and cybersecurity threats. With increased data-sharing across departments, external partners, and cloud-based data platforms like Snowflake, protecting sensitive information becomes paramount. Dynamic masking of shared Snowflake objects emerges not just as a technical convenience, but as an essential best practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
