<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Runink</title>
    <link>https://runink.org/tags/runink/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Runink</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:34:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://runink.org/tags/runink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Digital Twin? How Agentic Decisions Are Reshaping the Supply Chain</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/digital-twin-agentic-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/digital-twin-agentic-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-the-emergence-of-the-supply-chain-digital-twin&#34;&gt;1. The Emergence of the Supply Chain Digital Twin&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the intricate, globally distributed machinery of international trade and logistics, visibility has historically been the primary operational bottleneck. For decades, supply chain managers have relied on fragmented dashboards, delayed Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) messages, and manual updates to track the movement of goods. However, as global trade networks grow exponentially more complex and resilient logistics become a board-level imperative, merely &lt;em&gt;seeing&lt;/em&gt; a delayed shipment or a low inventory alert is no longer sufficient. Enter the &lt;strong&gt;Digital Twin&lt;/strong&gt;—a concept that is fundamentally altering how organizations interact with physical reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bill of Lading: The Swiss Army Knife of Global Trade</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/what-is-bill-of-lading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/what-is-bill-of-lading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-why-one-piece-of-paper-rules-the-ocean&#34;&gt;Introduction: Why One Piece of Paper Rules the Ocean&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;International trade relies on a sophisticated machinery of trust, but at its heart lies a single piece of paper: the &lt;strong&gt;Bill of Lading (BoL)&lt;/strong&gt;. It acts as the &amp;ldquo;Master Key&amp;rdquo; to global commerce, bridging the gap between parties separated by oceans, time zones, and disparate legal systems. For shippers and dropshippers alike, this document is the only thing standing between a profitable transaction and a total loss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Transportation: How Runink&#39;s AI Powers Modal Shift and Route Optimization</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/runink-ai-modal-shift-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/runink-ai-modal-shift-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Runink’s AI assistant helps logistics teams make smarter modal-shift decisions by integrating real-time rail and road data. It enhances transport efficiency, lowers operational costs, and supports sustainability—all without the need for massive analytics budgets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;revolutionizing-transportation-how-runinks-ai-powers-modal-shift-and-route-optimization&#34;&gt;Revolutionizing Transportation: How Runink&amp;rsquo;s AI Powers Modal Shift and Route Optimization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a rapidly evolving global logistics landscape, achieving efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and sustainability is crucial. Inefficient transport networks, especially the interchange between rail and truck services, frequently result in under-utilized capacity and increased operational costs. Recent disruptions, such as rising geopolitical tensions impacting key shipping routes, underline the importance of agile, responsive transport optimization. Runink, an advanced AI assistant, steps into this complex scenario with powerful AI-driven solutions for modal shift analysis and real-time route optimization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
