<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Route Optimization on Runink</title>
    <link>https://runink.org/tags/route-optimization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Route Optimization on Runink</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:19:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://runink.org/tags/route-optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Transportation: How Runink&#39;s AI Powers Modal Shift and Route Optimization</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/runink-ai-modal-shift-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/runink-ai-modal-shift-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Runink’s AI assistant helps logistics teams make smarter modal-shift decisions by integrating real-time rail and road data. It enhances transport efficiency, lowers operational costs, and supports sustainability—all without the need for massive analytics budgets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;revolutionizing-transportation-how-runinks-ai-powers-modal-shift-and-route-optimization&#34;&gt;Revolutionizing Transportation: How Runink&amp;rsquo;s AI Powers Modal Shift and Route Optimization&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a rapidly evolving global logistics landscape, achieving efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and sustainability is crucial. Inefficient transport networks, especially the interchange between rail and truck services, frequently result in under-utilized capacity and increased operational costs. Recent disruptions, such as rising geopolitical tensions impacting key shipping routes, underline the importance of agile, responsive transport optimization. Runink, an advanced AI assistant, steps into this complex scenario with powerful AI-driven solutions for modal shift analysis and real-time route optimization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
