<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Quality on Runink</title>
    <link>https://runink.org/tags/data-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Quality on Runink</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:47:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://runink.org/tags/data-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Automated Semantic Layers from Telemetry Events Are the Pillars of Data Observability Platforms</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/automated-semantic-layer-data-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/automated-semantic-layer-data-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-automated-semantic-layers-from-telemetry-events-are-the-pillars-of-data-observability-platforms&#34;&gt;Why Automated Semantic Layers from Telemetry Events Are the Pillars of Data Observability Platforms&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the era of streaming data, AI copilots, and self-service analytics, one truth has become unavoidable: &lt;strong&gt;you can’t observe what you can’t define&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Enter the &lt;strong&gt;automated semantic layer&lt;/strong&gt; — the missing connective tissue between raw telemetry and meaningful business context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When powered by continuous telemetry events, an automated semantic layer transforms fragmented observability metrics into &lt;strong&gt;a governed, contextual map of your entire data ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It’s how modern organizations are turning data observability from passive monitoring into &lt;strong&gt;active, explainable intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why ISO 8000, ISO 27000, ISO 27017, ISO 27018, ISO 42001 &amp; ISO 27701 Matter for Data‑Driven Business Success</title>
      <link>https://runink.org/blog/iso-standards-data-driven-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://runink.org/blog/iso-standards-data-driven-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Implementing ISO 8000, ISO 27000, ISO 27017, ISO 27018, ISO 42001, and ISO 27701 together forms a &lt;strong&gt;holistic framework&lt;/strong&gt; that strengthens data quality, security, privacy, and AI governance—laying a &lt;strong&gt;trustworthy foundation for data‑driven growth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-reliable-secure-and-privacycentric-data-foundations-with-iso-8000-iso-27000-iso-27017-iso-27018-iso-42001-and-iso-27701&#34;&gt;Building Reliable, Secure, and Privacy‑Centric Data Foundations with ISO 8000, ISO 27000, ISO 27017, ISO 27018, ISO 42001, and ISO 27701&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern enterprises thrive on data. From predictive analytics that steer product development to AI‑powered customer engagement, &lt;strong&gt;data‑driven decision making&lt;/strong&gt; separates market leaders from the rest. Yet data is only as valuable as it is &lt;strong&gt;accurate, secure, and trustworthy&lt;/strong&gt;. A single breach, a privacy violation, or a flawed dataset can erode customer confidence and stall innovation. That is why a growing number of organizations are adopting a suite of internationally recognized standards—&lt;strong&gt;ISO 8000, ISO 27000, ISO 27017, ISO 27018, ISO 42001, and ISO 27701&lt;/strong&gt;—to create data foundations that are &lt;strong&gt;reliable, secure, and privacy‑centric&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
